Paetel, Karl O.; Papers ger072
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Pamphlet Collection, 1904-1974; 8
  - Jugendbewegung - Youth, 1921-1974; 8.1
    - Authored pamphlets: Weniger, Erich. Deutsche Jugend (n.d.)., Undated (Box 44, Folder 93)
    - Authored pamphlets: Wolf, Hans. Gedenkheft für Herbert Charlet (n.d.)., Undated (Box 44, Folder 94)
    - Authored pamphlets: Wolf, Hans. Vom Ludwigstein, vom Archiv und der Jugendbewegung. Ein Vortrag (1974). (Box 44, Folder 95)
    - Authored pamphlets: Zeidler, Kurt. Vom erziehenden Eros (1920). (Box 44, Folder 96)
    - Authored pamphlets: Zimmermann, Werner. Auf schweizer Flüssen. Führer für Wasser-Wanderer und andere Freunde unberührter Natur (1925). (Box 44, Folder 97)
  - Refugees - Expellees, 1946-1966; 8.2
    These pamphlets deal predominately with conditions in post-war Germany and problems of refugees displaced during and immediately following World War II.
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Appendices to The Integration of Refugees into German Life (1951). (Box 44, Folder 98)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Are Refugees an Asset? PEP (Political and Economic Planning) pamphlet (ca. 1941). (Box 44, Folder 99)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Aufbau im Flüchtlingsland (1948). (Box 44, Folder 100)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Die Auswanderung. Ein Mittel zur Lösung der deutschen Frage? (1950). (Box 44, Folder 101)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Care and Help for the Expellees, Refugees, Immigrants, Evacuees, War Victims, Returnees, Prisoners of War, Homeless Foreigners, Political Refugees from abroad, Repatriated Persons, Emigrants. By the Federal Ministry for Expellees, Refugees and War Victims, Bonn (1955). (Box 44, Folder 102)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Charta der Deutschen Heimatvertriebenen / Charter of the German Expellees / Charte des Expulsés Allemands / Carta de los Expulsados Alemanes (1950). (Box 44, Folder 103)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Denkmal und Verheissung. Pressestimmen aus aller Welt zu dem Buche "Dokumente der Menschlichkeit" (1951). (Box 44, Folder 104)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Das deutsche Flüchtlingsproblem (1950). (Box 44, Folder 105)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Dunkle Geschäfte über die Grenze (n.d., 1950)., Undated (Box 44, Folder 106)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Emigration. A Means of Solving the German Problem? (1950). (Box 44, Folder 107)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:The expellees in the German Federal Republic (Western Germany) and their importance to Europe (June 1950)., 1950 June (Box 44, Folder 108)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:FACTS Concerning the Problem of the German Expellees and Refugees (n.d., 1958)., Undated (Box 44, Folder 109)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Flight from the Soviet Zone. 5 th ed. (1961). (Box 44, Folder 110)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Flüchtlinge in Niedersachsen (1949). (Box 44, Folder 111)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Die Flüchtlinge in Schleswig-Holstein. Die Ergebnisse der Flüchtlingssonder-Aerhebung des Landessozialministers Schleswig-Holstein (1950). (Box 44, Folder 112)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Flüchtlingsprobleme in Asien und Afrika (1966). (Box 44, Folder 113)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Germany's Eastern Territories. A European Problem (1950). (Box 44, Folder 114)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Die gewerblichen Vertriebenen- und Flüchtlingsbetriebe. Erfolge und ungelöste Aufgaben der Eingliederung (1955). (Box 44, Folder 115)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Grundgedanken zu einem Bevölkerungsausgleich in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland (1950). (Box 44, Folder 116)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Heimkehrer. Die Heimat grüßt Euch (1946). (Box 44, Folder 117)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Hessen und das Flüchtlingsproblem. Ein Rechenschaftsbericht der Zahlen und Tatsachen (1949). (Box 44, Folder 118)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Jeder Fünfte (n.d., 1961)., Undated (Box 44, Folder 119)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:The Land of the Dead. Study of the Deportations From Eastern Germany (n.d.)., Undated (Box 44, Folder 120)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Men Without the Rights of Men. A Report on the Expulsion and Extermination of German speaking Minority Groups in the Balkans and prewar Poland (n.d., 1947)., Undated (Box 44, Folder 121)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Die Not eines Landes! Denkschrift über Schleswig-Holstein (1948). (Box 44, Folder 122)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Notizen über den besetzten deutschen Osten und das Flüchtlingsproblem (n.d.)., Undated (Box 44, Folder 123)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Die Ostdeutschen Landsmannschaften. Vom landsmannschaftlichen Gedanken (1951). (Box 44, Folder 124)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Ostliteratur. Schicksal, Probleme und Beitrag der deutschen Heimatvertriebenen. Ein literarischer Wegweiser (1951). (Box 44, Folder 125)
    - The Problem of the Displaced Persons (June 1946)., 1946 June (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - The Refugee Problem Today (1948). (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Refugees Flooding the Island of Berlin (1953). (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Screened for Survival (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Some Facts About Expellees in Germany 1949 (1949). (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Some Facts About Expellees in Germany 1952 (1952). (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Tatsachen zum deutschen Vertriebenenproblem 1952 (1952). (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Die Umsiedler und die Oder-Neisse Grenze (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Volk im Volke. Zum Problem der Ostflüchtlinge im Westen (1949). (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Was geschah für Heimatvertriebene, Flüchtlinge, Kriegsgefangene, in der Bundesrepublik? (n.d., 1953)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Werden und Wirken des BHE (1951). (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Zwischen Krieg und Frieden. Flüchtlingsprobleme in Schleswig-Holstein / Between war and peace. Refugee Problems in Schleswig-Holstein (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Authored pamphlets:Barton, Betty. The Problem of 12 Million German Refugees In Today's Germany (1949). (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Authored pamphlets:Betz, Hanna. Flüchtlingsschicksal auf dem Lande. Untersuchung über die Situation der Heimatvertriebenen in der Gemeinde Holzhausen am Starnberger See (1949). (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Authored pamphlets:Granicky, Günter. Die Flüchtlinge in Nordrhein-Westfalen. Ergebnisse der Flüchtlingszählung 1947 (1949). (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Authored pamphlets:Hoehler, Fred K. Europe's Homeless Millions (1945). (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Authored pamphlets:Hofmann, Holger. Die Notlage der europäischen Kinder nach dem Kriege (1946). (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Authored pamphlets:Lüdemann, Hermann. Die Flüchtlinge in Schleswig-Holstein (1949). (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Authored pamphlets:Lukaschek, Hans. Die deutschen Heimatvertriebenen und ihre Bedeutung für Europa (1950). (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Authored pamphlets:Lukaschek, Hans. The German Expellees. A German Focal Problem (1950). (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Authored pamphlets:Piros, Mark. The Disillusioned: Twelve Million Refugees From Communism (1959). (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Authored pamphlets:Reitzner, Richard. Vom Ostwind verweht ... Das Schicksal von Millionen (1948). (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Authored pamphlets:Samaan, Emile. The Arab Refugees After Five Years. An Eyewitness Report (1953). (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Authored pamphlets:Stareck, Friedrich-Ludwig. Lebensfragen des deutschen Flüchtlings (1946). (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Authored pamphlets:Weidlein, Johann. Hintergründe der Vertreibung der Deutschen aus Ungarn. Eine historische Studie (1953). (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - Widerstand, 1937-1954; 8.3
    - Unauthored pamphlets:The Protestant Opposition Movement in Germany 1934-1937 (n.d., 1937)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:They Fought Hitler First. A Report on the Treatment of German Anti-Nazis in Concentration Camps from 1933 to 1939. Based on Contemporary Records (1945). (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Wider die trägen Herzen. Zur zehnjährigen Widerkehr des "20. Juli 1944" (1954). (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Widerstandskampf vor Gericht (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:20. Juli 1944 (1946). (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Der 20. Juli 1944 (1954). (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:20. Juli. Gedenkworte des Grafen York von Wartenburg vor Freunden des "Laupheimer Kreies" am 20. Juli 1952 (1952). (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - Authored pamphlets:Almond, Gabriel A. How Many Anti-Nazi Germans? (1946). (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - Authored pamphlets:Franke, Vera. Some Recent Information on Anti-Nazi Developments Among German Youth (1945). (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - Authored pamphlets:Heuss, Theodor. Dank und Bekenntnis. Gedenkrede zum 20. Juli 1944 (1954). (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - Authored pamphlets:Henk, Emil. Die Tragödie des 20. Juli 1944. Ein Beitrag zur politischen Vorgeschichte (1946). (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - Authored pamphlets:John, Otto. Ich wählte Deutschland (1954). (Box 45, Folder 37)
    - Authored pamphlets:Lend, Evelyn. The Underground Struggle in Germany (1938). (Box 45, Folder 38)
    - Authored pamphlets:Niemoeller, D. Martin. Die Aufgabe der evangelischen Kirche in Deutschland (1954). (Box 45, Folder 39)
    - Authored pamphlets:________. Deutschland wohin? Krieg oder Frieden? (1952). (Box 45, Folder 40)
    - Authored pamphlets:________. Können wir noch etwas tun zur friedlichen Wiedervereinigung unseres Volkes? (1955). (Box 45, Folder 41)
    - Authored pamphlets:Roeder, M. Die Rote Kapelle (1952). (Box 45, Folder 42)
    - Authored pamphlets:Schorn, Hubert. Das Widerstandsrecht in sittlicher und rechtlicher Beleuchtung (1953). (Box 45, Folder 43)
    - Authored pamphlets:Stillfried, A. Die österreichische Widerstandsbewegung und ihr Rückhalt im Volk. Vortrag, im großen Musikvereinsaal gehalten am 17.6.1946 (1946). (Box 45, Folder 44)
    - Authored pamphlets:Vossler, F. Gedenkrede für die Opfer an der Universität München (1947). (Box 45, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous topics, 1904-1974; 8.4
    - Unauthored pamphlets:A First Step toward school integration (1958). (Box 45, Folder 46)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:A "Freedom Budget" for All Americans. Budgeting Our Resources, 1966-1975 to Achieve "Freedom from Want" (1966). (Box 45, Folder 47)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:A Primer on Communism. 200 Questions and Answers (April 1956)., 1956 April (Box 45, Folder 48)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:A Program for a Democratic Germany (1944). (Box 45, Folder 49)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:A Rational Inquiry into Roles Played by Dr. Ivan L. Bennett, Jr. & New York University in The Utilization and Development of Technical and Human Resources for The U.S. Government's Chemical Biological Weapons Program and Military Policies (1970). (Box 45, Folder 50)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Abschied von Christoph Schrempf (1946). (Box 45, Folder 51)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Aggression from the North. The Record of North Viet-Nam's Campaign To Conquer South Viet-Nam (1965). (Box 45, Folder 52)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Aktuelle Wirtschaftsprobleme Schwedens (1951). (Box 45, Folder 53)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Albert Schweitzer-Buchpreis 1957. (Box 45, Folder 54)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Alto Adige in the World Press 1960-61 (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 55)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:America is on Trial: The Indian Goes to Court (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 56)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:American Conversations. Extremism in America Today. An Interview with Clifford P. Case, Morris B. Abram, Robert F. Kennedy (1966). (Box 45, Folder 57)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:American Interests in the Middle East (1969). (Box 45, Folder 58)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Der Ami-Käfer fliegt in den kalten Krieg! (n.d., 1950)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 59)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:An die Delegierten zum Bundesparteitag 1968 der Freiheitlichen Partei Österreichs (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 60)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Anti-Semitic Activity in the United States. A Report and Approval (1954). (Box 45, Folder 61)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:The Anti-Semitic Nature of the Czechoslovak Trial (Nov.-December 1952) (1952). (Box 45, Folder 62)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Appell an das Weltgewissen (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 63)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Arbeit und Brot! (1932). (Box 45, Folder 64)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Arbeiten, arbeiten, arbeiten! Die "neuen Rechte" der Frau in der Sowjetzone (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 65)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Arbeiter! Suchst Du eine proletarische Bildungsstätte? (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 66)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Der Arztberuf in der Sowjetzone (n.d., 1953)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 67)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:As the UN Probes Prejudice. Observations on The United Nations Inquiry into Anti-Semitism and Other Forms of Religious and Racial Prejudice (Sept. 1960)., 1960 September (Box 45, Folder 68)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Assault Upon Freedom of Association. A Study of the Southern Attack on the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (1957). (Box 45, Folder 69)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:The Atomic Arming of the West German Federal Republic – an Imminent Danger to World Peace (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 70)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:auf dem Wege zur Kolchose. Die Sowjetisierung der Landwirtschaft in der Sowjetzone (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 71)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Aufklärung als Waffe der Ausschüsse der Nationalen Front des demokratischen Deutschland (n.d., 1950)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 72)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Aufzeichnung über die Verletzung der Menschenrechte in der Sowjetischen Besatzungszone Deutschlands (Sept. 1966)., 1966 September (Box 45, Folder 73)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Augen auf! Kommunismus durch die Hintertür (1951). (Box 45, Folder 74)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Aus der Fabrik des Sowjetmenschen (n.d., 1953)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 75)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Auskunft über die Sowjetzone Deutschlands (1965). (Box 45, Folder 76)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Automation Crisis!! How Safe is YOUR Job? (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 77)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Automation, tool of the future (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 78)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:The Axis System of Hostages (1942). (Box 45, Folder 79)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Das befreiende Regierungsprogramm. Zur überparteilichen Aktion des Freiwirt-schaftsbundes (1932). (Box 45, Folder 80)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Beiträge zur totalen Demokratie (1948). (Box 45, Folder 81)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Bericht über den Aufbau der Volkspolizei in der sowjetischen Besatungszone (Stand: Frühjahr 1951)., 1951 March (Box 45, Folder 82)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Bericht über die Rüstungsproduktion in der sowjetischen Besatzungszone (Stand: Frühjahr 1951)., 1951 March (Box 45, Folder 83)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berlin August 13 (Sept. 1961); 2 nd ed. (April 1965)., 1961 September; 1965 April (Box 45, Folder 84)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berlin, 13. August (Sept. 1961)., 1961 September (Box 45, Folder 85)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berlin: Crisis and Challenge (n.d.)., Undated (Box 45, Folder 86)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berlin – fate and mission (1959). (Box 45, Folder 87)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berlin – Friedrichstraße 20.53 Uhr (1965). (Box 45, Folder 88)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berlin im Neuaufbau (1946). (Box 45, Folder 89)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berlin im Neuaufbau (1947). (Box 45, Folder 90)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berlin – in brief (1972). (Box 45, Folder 91)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berlin und die Mauer. Fragen Probleme Antworten (1967). (Box 45, Folder 92)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Berliner Begleiter (1958). (Box 45, Folder 93)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Die Berliner Konferenz und unsere Aufgaben (n.d., 1945?0., Undated (Box 45, Folder 94)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Die Bewaffnung der Bundesrepublik. Leitbrief der Freunde der "Stätte der Begegnung", No. 1 (February 1952)., 1952 February (Box 45, Folder 95)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Bigotry in Action. Organized Anti-Semitism in the United States Today (Sept. 1963)., 1963 September (Box 45, Folder 96)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Das Bollwerk der Nation. Bedeutung der Gründung und Existenz der Deutschen Demokratischen Republik für das Ringen der Nationalen Front um ein einheitliches demokratisches Deutschland und für den Frieden (1950). (Box 45, Folder 97)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Der Bolschewismus als Kernproblem der Gegenwart. Leitbrief der "Stätte der Begegnung", No. 7/8 (June 1953)., 1953 June (Box 45, Folder 98)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Brief an Frankreich von einem Deutschen (1946). (Box 45, Folder 99)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Brief History of the American Labor Movement (1951). (Box 45, Folder 100)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Britain Against Germany 1939-1945. A Record in Pictures (1945). (Box 45, Folder 101)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Buch der Freunde. Hrsg. Vom Komitee zum 70. Geburtstag von Harry Schulze-Wilde (1969). (Box 45, Folder 102)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Build a Base in the Working Class (June 1969)., 1969 June (Box 45, Folder 103)
    - Unauthored pamphlets:Das Bundesministerium für gesamtdeutsche Fragen (1959). (Box 45, Folder 104)
    - Capitalism Is Bankrupt ... It Can't Function Except on War Basis (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - The Case of Archbishop Stepinac (1947). (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Charta der deutschen Heimatvertriebenen / Charter of the German Expellees (1950). (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Chino Escape Frame-Up (1972). (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Church, State and the Public Schools. A Citizen's Handbook (n.d., 1961)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - The CIO and World Affairs. 2 nd ed. (April 1951)., 1951 April (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Civil Rights: ... Only a Step to Complete Freedom (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Common Council for American Unity (n.d., 1952?)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Confuse and Control. Soviet Techniques in Germany (April 1951)., 1952 April (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - The Crimes of the Stalin Era (July 16, 1956)., 1956 July 16 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Current Anti-Semitic Activities Abroad. A Survey (June 1963)., 1963 June (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - The Current Situation in Germany (May 1949)., 1949 May (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - D.A.R. Manual for Citizenship (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Death and Resurrection in the Life of Nations. A Radio Discussion by William Hocking, Charles Merriam, Reinhold Niebuhr and Robert Redfield (April 1, 1945)., 1945 April 1 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Das Demokratische Deutschland. Grundsätze und Richtlinien für den deutschen Wiederaufbau im demokrtischen, republikanischen, föderalistischen und genossenschaftlichen Sinne (1945). (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Deutsche, mit- oder gegeneinander? (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Das Deutsche Volk und die Vereinten Nationen (1966). (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Deutsches Land dem deutschen Volk! Die Umwandlung von Großgütern, Staatsdomänen und Fideikommissen in Heinstätten-Kolonien als wirtschaftliche Erwerbs-Genossenschaften (1931). (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Deutschland – Belgien, 1830-1945. Empfehlungen der belgisch-deutschen Historikerkonferenz Braunschweig 1954 (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Deutschland und die Vereinigten Staaten. Empfehlungen der 2. amerikanisch-deutschen Historikerkonferenz über die Behandlung der amerikanisch-deutschen Beziehungen vom 18. Jahrhundert bis 1941. Braunschweig, 23. bis 31. August 1955 (1955). (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Deutschland und England 1904-1914. Empfehlungen der englisch-deutschen Historikertagung 1955 (1955). (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - Deutschland und Österreich 1700-1848. Empfehlungen der 1. deutsch-österreichischen Historikertagung. Braunschweig, 9. bis 12. April 1956 (1956). (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - Die Diskussion vor dem "IV. Deutschen Schriftstellerkongreß" in Ostberlin (1955). (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - Dokumentation der Unmenschlichkeit gegenüber deutschen Kriegsgefangenen und Zivilverschleppten in der UdSSR (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - Dokumentation des Terrors. Namen und Schicksale der seit 1945 in der sowjetisch besetzten Zone Deutschlands verhafteten und verschleppten Professoren und Studenten (March 1962)., 1962 March (Box 46, Folder 25)
    - Dokumente der 5. Kolonne (n.d., 1950?)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 26)
    - Die dritte Norm der Generale Korfes, Lattmann, Bamler, Lenski und Genossen (n.d., 1959)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 27)
    - Economic and Political Situation in Europe. Series B: Summaries of Newspapersand Periodicals on Special Topics. Effects of Bombings in Germany III, May 1943 (July 1943). (Box 46, Folder 28)
    - The Economic, Social and Domestic Conditions of the Schoolchildren in Post-War Bremen (1947). (Box 46, Folder 29)
    - Educational and Cultural Activities in Germany Today (1950). (Box 46, Folder 30)
    - The Eichmann Case in the American Press (August 1962)., 1962 August (Box 46, Folder 31)
    - Ein ernstes Wort an alle Deutschamerikaner (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 32)
    - Ein großer Tag in der Geschichte unserer Stadt. 26. Juni 1963: John F. Kennedy in Berlin (1963). (Box 46, Folder 33)
    - Ein Kampf um Deutschland (1933). (Box 46, Folder 34)
    - Ein Schandmal im Urteil der Welt. Äusserungen ausländischer Politiker angesichts der Mauer (May 1962)., 1962 May (Box 46, Folder 35)
    - Entschließung der 4. Landesdelegierten-Konferenz der Sozialistischen Einheits-partei Deutschlands, Landesverband Sachsen, Dresden, Jurhaus Bühlau, 9. bis 11. Dez. 1949. (Box 46, Folder 36)
    - Entwurf einer Verfassung für die Deutsche Demokratische Republik (December 1946)., 1946 December (Box 46, Folder 37)
    - Enzensberger'sche Einzelheiten, korrigiert von der Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung (June 1963)., 1963 June (Box 46, Folder 38)
    - Erklärung des Parteivorstandes der KPD zur politischen Lage (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 39)
    - Erklärung gegen das Wiedererstehen des deutschen Militarismus (n.d., 1951)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 40)
    - Ernst Thälmann proklamiert: Bauernhilfsprogramm der kommunistischen Partei (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 41)
    - Der 1. Mai (April 1946)., 1946 April (Box 46, Folder 42)
    - Erwachendes Volk. Briefe an Leutnant a.D. Scheringer (1931). (Box 46, Folder 43)
    - Es stand in "Opposition und Ziel" (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 44)
    - Euer Herz erschrecke nicht! Gottesdienst am Himmelfahrtsfest 10. Mai 1945 (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 45)
    - Euratom. The European Atomic Energy Community (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 46)
    - Die europäische Bedeutung der Oder-Neisse-Gebiete (July 1955)., 1955 July (Box 46, Folder 47)
    - Ex-Nazis in the service of the "German Democratic Republic" (n.d.)., Undated (Box 46, Folder 48)
    - Eyewitness Report IV on Germany 1941 (February 1943)., 1943 February (Box 46, Folder 49)
    - F.O. Matthiessen (1902-1965). A Collective Portrait (October 1950)., 1950 October (Box 46, Folder 50)
    - Facts vs. Propaganda. The Truth about "Right to Work" Laws (December 1957)., 1957 December (Box 46, Folder 51)
    - Faschismus in der Kurzschrift (April 1947)., 1947 April (Box 46, Folder 52)
    - Faschismus? Nein! Sozialismus! Die Arbeit der Sozialdemokratie im Reichstag (1930). (Box 46, Folder 53)
    - Der Faschismus und die Intellektuellen. Untergang des Deutschen Geistes (1934). (Box 46, Folder 54)
    - Feinde der Gewerkschaften. Feinde der Demokratie. Tatsachen und Dokumente (October 1950)., 1950 October (Box 46, Folder 55)
    - Ferdinand Avenarius, 1856-1923 (1961). (Box 46, Folder 56)
    - Foreign Relations of the United States (June 1948)., 1948 May (Box 46, Folder 57)
    - Forschung heisst Arbeit und Brot (Sept. 1950)., 1950 September (Box 46, Folder 58)
    - Freedom Through Dissent. 42 nd Annual Report, July 1, 1961 to June 30, 1962. American Civil Liberties Union., Undated (Box 46, Folder 59)